HR PROJECT MANAGER

Summary

A highly adaptable, motivated, HR professional that enjoys details, developing strategies, and providing practical solutions. Demonstrated ability to learn quickly, communicate effectively, and establish relationships across various levels of an organization. Experience in employee relations, process improvement, project management, policy harmonization, vendor relationships, policy development, leadership, recruiting, performance management, and organizational development.

Highlights

Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Publisher, EV4, SAP, Enterprise E-time, Sharepoint Leadership Lafayette Graduate, 2010 Active in local church by organizing annual spring women's retreat and teaching Sunday school

Experience

Labcorp March 2013 to Current HR Project Manager

Matthews, NC

- Project manager for various centers of expertise within HR to provide project support on a national level as needed.
- Engage with others and lead, or assist with, initiatives to drive process optimization which includes streamlining and harmonizing HR business
 practices, policies, processes, and vendors.
- Project manager for outsourcing of FMLA and Short Term Disability to a third party vendor for all of Evonik US.
- Responsibilities include leading HR team, Request for Proposal process, vendor selection, communication, and implementation of program
- Working with third party vendor to design process for tuition degree approvals and reimbursement within new HR Direct system Serving as
 part of an internal team to benchmark and network in order to develop and implement harmonized HR policies and procedures across US,
 including leading the effort on the FMLA, short term disability, and tuition policies Leading team to research and implement new time
 tracking software for Evonik US Leading the Evonik Employee Survey Team at a production site with approximately 550 employees.
- Received excellent response rate from survey, communicated results, led committee to gather employee feedback, developed and helped implement site action plan in response to areas of concern.
- Engaged with site leadership to create new job descriptions for production site.
- Over 175 job descriptions created in approximately one year.

Evonik Industries Eli Lilly & Company September 2009 to March 2013 HR Generalist/Consultant City , STATE

- Served as business partner for various departments to provide organizational design and staffing support.
- Represented employees, management, and the company to ensure best decisions were made for the business as a whole.
- Worked closely with management to recruit and onboard new employees, administer the performance management process, investigate
 workplace issues, disciplinary situations, manage leave of absence, create HR policies and address questions related to compensation,
 benefits, and policies.
- Responsible for general HR duties, such as compensation, benefits, absence management, and investigations, for approximately 300 employees covering various shifts Led recruiting and onboarding efforts by meeting with managers to discuss needs, screen candidates, conduct phone and on-site interviews, facilitate candidate assessments, write offer letters, and develop new employee orientation for several technical positions including Innovation Management, Engineering, Maintenance, IT, and Procurement Provided guidance in determining job levels for dozens of exempt and non-exempt positions Developed employee handbook addressing issues such as discrimination, absence management, disciplinary procedures, and pay practices Presented to various levels of the organization on performance management and HR policies for training purposes.
- Coordinated with external resources to provide management training.
- Managed on-site medical staff including two full time nurses and a contract physician Assisted with the sale of the plant site by answering
 employee questions and overseeing document collection for onboarding over 600 employees within a two day period.

April 2007 to September 2009 Leader

- Supervised team consisting of five to nine direct reports in both quality control and environmental laboratory settings.
- Responsible for maintenance budget, ensured sample testing completed within required timeframe and quality standards, and laboratory
 equipment was qualified.
- Coordinated and scheduled work for staff weekly to ensure testing completed as required by regulatory agencies (FDA, IDEM, EPA)
 Established performance expectations and conducted routine performance reviews Facilitated cross training of employees in multiple areas
 of the laboratory Conducted and documented investigations using root cause analysis techniques Responsible for maintenance budget and
 forecasting laboratory equipment needs Served as root cause expert for the plant site by reviewing production deviations to ensure root
 cause was found.

June 2003 to April 2007 Analytical Chemist - Quality Control

- Performed assays involving high performance liquid chromatography, gas chromatography, and wet chemistry techniques.
- Provided technical guidance and troubleshooting for raw materials and final API testing.
- Performed hundreds of assays in a GMP environment using HPLC, GC, and wet chemistry techniques with minimal errors using good documentation practices.
- Responsible for writing annual product reports, regulatory reports, method validations, and performing technical reviews.
- Created new documentation templates and modified procedures so that laboratory testing could be completed more efficiently.

Education

2015 HR Certification: Human Resources Human Resources

Illinois Institute of TEchnology 2009 Master of Chemistry: Analytical Chemistry City, State GPA: 3.75 Analytical Chemistry GPA: 3.75 Michigan Technological University 2003 Bachelor of Science: Chemistry Biochemistry City, State GPA: 3.75 Chemistry Biochemistry GPA: 3.75 Chemistry Biochemistry GPA: 3.75

Skills

API, benefits, budget, documentation, forecasting, GC, GMP, HPLC, HR, Innovation, Leadership, letters, management training, materials, Excel, PowerPoint, Publisher, Word, Enterprise, network, optimization, organizational design, organizing, performance reviews, performance management, policies, processes, Procurement, Proposal, quality, quality control, recruiting, research, SAP, staffing, teaching, phone, troubleshooting